Preliminary Guide to the Frank Bardacke Papers M2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Frank Bardacke papers
1960-1990
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Adair, Doug
Hirsch, Fred
Govea, Jessica
Renteria, Jose
Magana, Luis
Camacho, Epifanio
Cohen, Jerry
Hirsch, Ginnie
Soria, Joseph
Zambrano, Aristeo
Pelayo, Chayo
Garcia, Robert
Vera Cruz, Philip, 1904-
Castrayon family
Bardacke, Frank
M2014
56 Linear Feet (39 cartons, 7 flat boxes, 7 cassette boxes, 2 map folders)
Frank Bardacke is a historian, author, educator, trade unionist, and political activist. Materials consist of interviews with UFW members as research for his book, Trampling Out the Vintage; research notes; drafts of manuscripts and other related materials.
Biographical / Historical
Frank Bardacke was active in the student and anti-war movements in Berkeley in the 1960s. He moved to California's Central Coast in 1970, worked for six seasons in the Salinas Valley fields, and taught at Watsonville Adult School for twenty-five years. He is the author of Trampling Out the Vintage: Cesar Chavez and the Two Souls of the United Farm Workers, Good Liberals and Great Blue Herons: Land, Labor and Politics in the Pajaro Valley, and a translator of Shadows of Tender Fury: The Letters and Communiqués of Subcomandante Marcos and the Zapatista Army of National Liberation. ---http://www.versobooks.com/authors/1245-frank-bardacke
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was purchased by Stanford University Library in 2014.
Scope and Contents
Series in this collection were derived from the creator; folder headings were transcribed from original folders. The collection was minimally rehoused and listed.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Agricultural laborers--California--History--20th Century; Labor disputes--California.; Labor history; Mexican American labor union members; Migrant agricultural laborers -- California.; United Farm Workers of America; Bardacke, Frank; Huerta, Dolores; Chavez, Cesar; Ross, Fred.; Padilla, Esther; Padilla, Gilbert; Mojica, Hermilio; Bustamente, Mario; Rojas, Albert; Espinoza, Pablo; Adair, Doug; Hirsch, Fred; Govea, Jessica; Renteria, Jose; Magana, Luis; Camacho, Epifanio; Cohen, Jerry; Hirsch, Ginnie; Soria, Joseph; Zambrano, Aristeo; Pelayo, Chayo; Garcia, Robert; Vera Cruz, Philip, 1904-; Castrayon family; Bardacke, Frank; Ganz, Marshall, 1943-
- Series 1: Trampling Out The Vintage: Manuscripts Drafts
  - Car Pool, 14A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Others, 14A (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - David Holt, 14A (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Battle Fields, 14A (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Work Itself, 14A (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Wobblies, 14A (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Thirties, 14A (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Alchemist, 14A (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Boycott, Baby, Boycott, 14A (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ganz Reuther, 14A (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Epi El Teatro, 14A (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Pilgrimage, 14A (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Digiorgo, 14A (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Texas Interlude, 14A (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cutting Back and Rooting Out, 14A (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Part 3 The Fast, 14A (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Boycott Victory, 14A (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Part 4: Salinas before the Storm, 14A (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Red Lettuce Alone Part 4, 14A (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Up on the Mountain, 14A (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Up on the Mountain, 14A (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Goons, Scabs, Pickets: 1973, 14A (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Felicia Barsi SST, 14A (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Living with the Law: The Good, The Bad, The Unlikely, 14A (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Victory in Hand, 14A (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The Last Great Strike, 14A (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Civil War, 14A (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Prologue 3/09, 14B (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Territory, 14B (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - The Work Itself, 14B (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Founding Ways Lay Catalogue Activist, 14B (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Childhood As Destiny, 14B (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - The Alchemist Jan 09, 14B (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Organizer in Oakland Jan 09, 14B (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - The River's Source, 14B (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - The Founding Family Jan 09, 14B (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Now Winos Jan 09, 14B (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - The Grape Strike Feb 09, 14B (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Moral Jujitsu, 14B (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Boycott, Baby, Boycott, 14B (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Battle Theater, 14B (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The Spring Pilgrimage March 04, 14B (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Democratic Delanto, 14B (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Cutting Back and R.O., 14B (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - The Fast, 14B (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Salinas Before the Storm, 14B (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Boycott Heroics, 14B (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Red Lettuce Alone, 14B (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Up on the Mountain, 14B (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Fighting For Our Lives, 14B (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - The Grand Concession, 14B (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - The Wet Line, 14B (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Living with the Law, 14B (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - The Game, 14B (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - DDCC Go Crazy, 14B (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - "That Wall is Black", 14B (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - The Last Great Strike, 14B (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Esta Huelga Esta, 14B (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Victory in Hand, 14B (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Civil War, 14B (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Exeunt Omnes, 14B (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Epilogue, 14B (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - From This Valley, 14C (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fast Notes, 14C (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Fast, 14C (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chapter 5 The Flowering of Democratic Delano, 14C (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Victoria Notes, 14C (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Triumph, 14C (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pablo Camacho, 14C (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Salinas, 14C (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reds Letter Alone, 14C (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Salinas is Other, 14C (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Econ Notes, 14C (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Strike Prelude, 14C (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1970 Salinas Outliner, 14C (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Flowering The Digiorno Campaign, 14C (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fast Notes, 14C (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1971-73, 14C (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Boycott, 14C (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Boycott, Baby, Boycott, 14C (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Boycott, Baby, Boycott, 14C (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Boycott Draft, 14C (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The Spring Pilgrimage, 14C (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Boycott Victory, 14C (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Boycott Vicotory, 14C (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The Car Pool, 14C (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Raul Medina, 14C (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Braulio, 14C (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Chavez: Childhood as Destiny, 14C (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Jose Alvarado, 14C (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Franky, Pancho, Me, 14C (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - The Ong. In Oxnamo, 14C (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Mac Reference Card, 14C (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - The Others, 14C (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - [Carlson UFW and Civil Rights], 14C (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Pruning, 14C (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Part Three: Chapter six Texas Interlude, 14C (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Flower Notes Part 3 Chapter 5, 14C (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Attendence/Transfer Forms, 14C (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Updates, 14C (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Untitled, 14C (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - To Conect, 14C (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - The Secret of the Dove, 14C (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - The 1930s, 14C (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Native Amer., 14C (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Grape Strike, 14C (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - The Work Itself, 14C (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Oxnard, 14D (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Victory At Hand, Confusion at Heart, 14D (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - What Shape The Resurrection? and Afterword, 14D (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Last Great Strike, 14D (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Good, The Bad, The Unlikely, 14D (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "The Game", 14D (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Living with the Law, 14D (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Goons, Scabs, Pickets, 14D (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Wet Line, 14D (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Up on the Mountain, 14E (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Reds Lettuce Alone, 14E (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Salinas Before the Storm, 14E (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Triumph of Will and Organization, 14E (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Fast, 14E (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cutting Back and Rooting Out, 14E (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Texas Interlude, 14E (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Democratic Delanto, 14E (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Spicy Pilgrimage, 14E (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Battle Theater, 14E (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Boycott, Baby, Boycott, 14E (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Moral Jujitsu, 14E (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - The Grape Strike, 14E (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - New Wings, 14E (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Family, 14E (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The River's Source, 14E (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Alchemist, 14E (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Oxnard, 14E (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - The Org W Oxnard, 14E (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - The Lay Catholic Activist, 14E (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - The Thirties, 14E (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Childhood As Destiny, 14E (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - The Work Itself, 14E (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - The Car Pool, 14E (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Maps / Ch. 1, 14E (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Prologues The Carpool, 14E (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Letter Joanne T.C., 14G (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Car Pool, 14G (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Car Pool, 14G (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chap 2 Mapping the Territory, 14G (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Battle Fields Maps, 14G (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Work Itself, 14G (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The Work Itself, 14G (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Work Itself, 14G (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Childhood As Destiny, 14G (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Childhood As Destiny, 14G (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lay Catholic Activist, 14G (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The Lay Catholic Activist, 14G (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Organizer in Oxard, 14G (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Book 1 Chap1 The River's Source, 14G (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The Black Eagle, 14G (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - New Wings, 14G (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Grape Strike, 14G (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Boycott, Baby, Boycott, 14G (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Ganz and Reuther, 14G (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Picket Lines Again, 14G (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - The Spring Pilgrimage, 14G (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - DiGiorgio Campaign, 14G (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Texas Interlude, 14G (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Cutting Back and Rooting Out, 14G (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Triumph of Will and Organization, 14G (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Salinas Before the Storm, 14G (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Reds Lettuce Alone, 14G (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Up in the Mountain, 14G (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Goons, Scabs, and Pickets, 14G (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - The Grand Concession, 14G (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Living with the Law, 14G (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - The Last Great Strike, 14G (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - The Good, The Bad, The Unlikely, 14G (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Civil War, 14G (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - What Shape the R.?, 14G (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Early Bibliography, 14H (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Tsuda College, 14H (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - The Battle Fields, 14H (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - The New Outline of Beneath the California Sun April 2000, 14H (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Paid Reps. Early Years, 14H (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - The River's Source, 14H (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - CSO - Oxnard, 14H (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - The Alchemist, 14H (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - The Serpent and the Dove, 14H (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - California for the Worker, 14H (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Optimism About Past, 14H (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - The Others, 14H (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Edited 1st Sector (No Guro), 14H (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Part 3 The Pilgrimage, 14H (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Biographical Extracts, 14H (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - [Bloompitios], 14H (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Car Pool, 14H (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Philosopher and the Provocateur, 14H (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Part III, Chap 1, 14H (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Part 3, Chap 4, 14H (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Part III, Chap 3, 14H (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Part III, Chap 2, 14H (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Part III, Chap 8, 14H (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Part III, Chap 7, 14H (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Part III, Chap 6, 14H (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The Pruning, 14H (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Part III, Chap 9, 14H (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Grape Strike, 14H (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 1930s and Org in Oxnard, 14H (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 1930s and Org in Oxnard, 14H (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 1930s and Org in Oxnard, 14H (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Part 3, Chapt 15, 14H (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Car Pool and Copies (1 of 3), 14H (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Car Pool and Copies (2 of 3), 14H (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Car Pool and Copies (3 of 3), 14H (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - NFWA Outlines, 15 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Founds, 15 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Secret and The Dove, 15 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - [Scheade] Notes, 15 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Pilgrimage Drafts, 15 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Notes for "The Others", 15 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - River's Source, 15 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Spring Pilgrimage, 15 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Long Outline, 15 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - AKA: The Valle w/ The Dead, 15 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Serpent and Dove, 15 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 87 Mazda P.U., 15 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - River's Source Imperial Valley, 15 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Car Pool, 15 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Notes, 15 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Battle Fields Maps, 15 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - The Car Pool, 15 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Car Pool JAF, 15 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Rosario Ackerman, 15 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Early Childhood Observation, 15 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Untitled, 15 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Big Outline, 15 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - The Battle Fields, 15 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - The Car Pool, 15 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Childhood As DestinyPart 2 Chapt 1, 15 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Car Pool, 15 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Prelude: Car Pools, 15 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - The Work Itself, 15 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - The Work Itself, 15 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - The Work Itself, 15 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Childhood As History, 15 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Goons, Scabs, Pickett 1973, 15 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Goons, Scabs, Pickets, 15 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Giving birth to the Black Eagle, 15 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Reds, Lettuce Alone, 15 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Up on the Mountain, 15 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Goons, Scabs and Picketts: 1973, 15 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Goons, Scabs, Picketts unedited, 15 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - NFWA Transformed, 15 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - NFWA Transformed, 15 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Red, Lettuce Alone, 15 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Series 2: Personal Files
  - Subseries 2.1: FJ Files
    - Hospital, FJ Files [Frank J Bardecke?] (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Mexico, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - City Loans, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Methyl Bromide, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - AG, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Adult BD, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Vicki Hoarn "How To Say Fetch", FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - UCSC Farm Work Course, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Yugoslavia, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Portrait of FJ, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Frank Bardacke - Airport, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Airport, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Alteranative Budget, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Methyl Bromide, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - School, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Land, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Watson, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - El [Temporo], FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - NAFTA, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Tom Miller, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Pesticides, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Ruth Weisberg, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Peta Foundation, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Sixties, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Seth's Papers, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Recent [communions], FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Letters to Jules Feiffer, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Oakland 7, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Mike Davis, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Ted, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - The Facts Speak for Themselves, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - La Revolucion Industrial de Mexico, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Flag, Faith, and family, FJ Files (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Subseries 2.2: Personal Files
    - Legal Rights of Teamsters, A (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Latino Culture, A (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Ecology and America India, A (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - The Californians Discover 1992, A (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - The California Missions: A Different view, A (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Notebook, A (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Notebook, A (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Hanke, A (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Watsonville Book, A (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, A (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Scuffling, A (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Guadalupe, A (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - History of the [Pajam Valley], A (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Material, A (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Miles/The [Door], A (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Journal, A (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - San Francisco Bay Area Labor History Workshop Directory 1994, A (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - School Funding, A (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Ismael, A (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Mike Miller, A (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Mexico and the United States Neighbors in Crisis, A (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper Clipping, A (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Red, Green, White, Brown Friends and Family, A (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Enterprise Zones, A (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Pinto [Lake], A (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Math Mastery Geometry and Algebra, A (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Franicia, A (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Water, A (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - General Plan, A (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Mexico, A (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - TDC, A (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Poverty S.C. Cont, B (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Voting, B (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Immigration, B (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Family Tree, B (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Other Workers Osha-Work Safety, B (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Sports/Declaration, B (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - July Stuff Meet, B (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Gulf War, B (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Technology, B (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Alteranative Budget, B (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Banks, B (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Israel, B (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - 1st Person Worker Statement, B (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Maxism - Loninism, B (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Southern Oral History Program, B (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - China, B (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Educacion Bilingue, B (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Yugoslavia, B (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Political Cartoons Humor, B (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Father Sieur, B (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Newspaper Trys, B (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Indians in Overalls, B (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Course Descriptions and Reading Lists, B (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Family, B (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Philipines, B (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Battered Wife, B (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - University, B (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Student Papers and Comments, B (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Economic Class, B (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Armed, B (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - History, B (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Teamsters, B (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, C (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous Material, C (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - GNS by Frank Bardacke, C (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - The Nation Publication, C (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Wazapata 3, C (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Brochures, C (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Don Thanks Again, Lets talk about including Cesar's Ghost, C (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous Material, C (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Misc. Writing, C (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Various Clipping, C (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Final Script, C (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous Material, C (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Stop-The-Draft Week, C (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, C (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript, C (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Letter, C (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Final Trial oj Juan Parra, C (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Material, C (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Spanish Act 3, C (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Clipping Print-Outs, C (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Magazine Sept. 1988, C (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Material, C (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Various Clippings, C (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - GNS by Frank Bardacke, C (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Memos 2004, D (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - John Borrego 221 College 8, D (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Ohana, D (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Complaint About Quality, D (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Various Pamphlets, D (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Fair-Share Service Fee Prayers' Notice, D (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Stuff to do, D (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Adult BD Contract, D (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Seniority List Perm Status, D (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Adult Education Program, D (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Material, D (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Social Security Administration, D (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Blue Cross Wellpoint, D (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Collective Bargaining Agreement, D (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Untitled Folder, D (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Rosa Martinez, D (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Ditto, D (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Micro Mons clips, D (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Notes, D (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous Material, D (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous Material, D (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous Material, D (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Harris, Wilkshire Grannis, D (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous Newspaper, D (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Newspapers, C (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    - Newspapers, C (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    - Newspapers, C (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    - Newspapers, C (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    - Newspapers, C (Flat-box 10, Folder 5)
    - Newspapers, C (Flat-box 10, Folder 6)
    - Newspapers, C (Flat-box 11, Folder 1)
    - Newspapers, C (Flat-box 11, Folder 2)
    - Newspapers, C (Flat-box 11, Folder 3)
    - Magazine Proceso edicion especial 1 de Enero 1999, E (Flat-box 11, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Letter, E (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Joses Attendence, E (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - JDU ALRB Case, E (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Material, E (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - TDU ALRB Case, E (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Various Notes, E (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Material, E (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Various Manuscripts, E (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, E (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - What means this Strike?, E (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Notes and Manuscripts, E (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - What means this Strike? Manuscript, E (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Material, E (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Material, E (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Strike Support Committee, E (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Various Pamphlets, E (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Material, E (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper Clippings, E (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - City, E (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - A Farmer's International?, E (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - A Guide to the USA Patriot Act Provisions..., E (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - AMPO, E (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Yangita Kunio's Critique of the Chrysanthemum and the Sword, E (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Rural California Report, E (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Monthly Review Foundation, E (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Newspaper Clippings, E (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Auntie Manuscript, E (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous Material, E (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Former Soviet Claim, E (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Cahil Prible '96, E (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Petra, E (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous Material, E (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - American Labor Radical History, E (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Negatives, E (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Photograph, E (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Monthly Review Press, E (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, E (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Reviews, E (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - UC Santa Cruz Chicano/a Latino Research Center, E (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Newspaper Clippings, E (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - National Geographic, E (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - National Geographic, E (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Retail Sale, F (Box 13, Folder 1)